vendhq.com 2018-12-26

# Vend | Privacy Policy | Vend

Introduction

This Privacy Policy was last updated on 17 April 2018, with changes taking effect at midnight (in your timezone) on 16 May 2018 or immediately for new Subscribers to Vend after 17 April 2018). 

This Privacy Policy explains how Vend Limited and its related companies (collectively, “Vend”, “us”, “we” or “our”) collect, use, disclose, transfer, protect, store and otherwise process your information. It also explains your rights and options around our use of your personal information and how you can exercise these choices.

Scope of privacy policy

Vend is committed to protecting the privacy of the individuals on Vend’s websites, mobile applications, products and services, (collectively, "Services") that include a link to this Privacy Policy. For the purposes of this Policy, “Subscriber”, as the term is used here, refers to an individual or an entity that registers to use our Services.

In this Privacy Policy, personal information means information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. An identifiable person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identification number or to one or more factors specific to his/her physical, physiological, mental, economic, cultural or social identity. By registering for or using Services you acknowledge the collection, transfer, processing, storage, disclosure and other uses of your information, as described in this Privacy Policy.

  * **Subscriber Information** , being personal information relating to our Subscribers and (where applicable) their businesses. We collect this information so that we can provide our Services to those Subscribers. For the purposes of GDPR in the European Union, we are the 'data controller' of this Subscriber Information and we collect and store it for the purposes of providing our Services to Subscribers and maintaining records and contact details relating to those Services and Subscribers. **This policy sets out how Vend process your information as a Subscriber.**

  * **Customer Information** , being personal information relating to individuals with whom our subscribers interact (such as customers of their stores). Subscribers to our Services are solely responsible for establishing policies for and ensuring compliance with all applicable laws and regulations, as well as all privacy policies, agreements or other obligations, relating to the collection of personal information in connection with the use of our Services by individuals with whom our Subscribers interact. We collect information under the direction of our Subscribers, and have no direct relationship with individuals whose personal information we process in connection with the use of our Services. If you are a Subscriber providing information (including personal information) about someone else, you must have the legal ability to do so and, if necessary, inform them about how their personal information will be used (as described in this Privacy Policy). **If you are an individual who interacts with a Subscriber using our Services - for instance if you’re an employee or customer of a retail store – that Subscriber is the controller of your information and you should contact them directly (e.g. - the owner or manager of the retail store) – for assistance with any requests or questions relating to your personal information.**

Your Information

In using our Services, you provide us with the following information which we store securely:

Account and Profile Information

  * Contact information such as name, email address, mailing address, phone number and country
  * Profile information such as a username, profile photo, and job role
  * Preferences information such as notification and marketing preferences

Operational Data

We also store information you upload to or send through our Services, including:

  * Information about products and services the Subscriber sells (including inventory, pricing, sale, transaction, tax, and other data)
  * Information about the Subscriber or the Subscriber’s business (employee, customer, and contact data)

Other Submissions

We ask for and collect personal information from you when you submit web forms on our websites or when you participate in any interactive features of our Services, participate in a survey, competition, promotion, activity or event, apply for a job, request customer support, download content, communicate with us via third party social media sites, or otherwise communicate with us.

What other information do we collect?

Access Logs

Like with most websites and services delivered over the Internet, we gather certain information and store it in log files when you interact with our websites and Services. This information includes Internet protocol (IP) addresses as well as browser type, URLs of referring/exit pages, operating system, language and location preferences, time/date stamp, search history, device identification numbers and system configuration information. Occasionally, we connect personal information to information gathered in our log files as is necessary to improve our Services. If we do this, we would treat the combined information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Analytics Information

We collect analytics information when you use our Services to help us improve our products and services. We are always aiming to make Vend a better experience for retailers and customers alike, and your information really helps us to do this! This analytics information consists of the function and feature of the Vend Service being used, and the Subscriber's Vend subdomain name (or similar), the username and IP address of the individual who is using the function or feature (which will include any personal information incorporated into the username), and other information needed to detail the operation of the function and the parts of the Services that are being affected.

We use Google Analytics as one of our analytics providers. Refer to [Google's Policies and Principles](https://www.google.com/policies/)o find out more about the privacy policy of Google Analytics. To prevent analytics information from being sent to Google Analytics, use the [Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

Analytics Information Derived from Operational Data

Analytics information also consists of data we collect as a result of running queries against Operational Data across our user base for the purposes of generating Usage Data. "Usage Data" is aggregated data about a category or group of features, services, or users that is not of itself personal information. It is also data about our Subscribers and their business.

We may incidentally come across sensitive or personal information when we compile Usage Data.

Cookies, Web Beacons and Other Tracking Technologie

Cookies, web beacons and other technologies are used by Vend and our third party partners (for example, our advertising and analytics partners) to collect information. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on your hard drive or in device memory for record keeping purposes. We use cookies to give you a better and more personalised use of the Services, to save you logging in every time and to count the number of visits. Vend and our third party partners also collect information using web beacons. Web beacons are objects embedded in our Services or in emails that assist us to check that Content has been accessed for web analytics. You may be able to opt out of receiving personalised advertisements as described below under [How you can protect Your information](https://www.vendhq.com/uk/privacy-policy#infouseage).

Information from third party services

We may also receive personal information from third parties such as social media, data enrichment or authentication services when, for example, you sign up to our Services, fill in forms on our Services or log onto our Services through such services. Any access we may have to such information is governed by the authorisation procedures of that service. By authorising us to connect with a third party service, you authorise us to access and store your name, email address(es), locale, profile picture URL, and other personal information that the third party service makes available to us, and to use and disclose it in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Check your privacy settings on these third party services to learn and modify the information these services send to us.

How Vend uses your information

We are continually striving to improve Vend. Being able to identify how retailers are using our product plays a big part in helping us to make our software better. We may use information about you for purposes such as:

  * Enabling you to access and use our Services
  * Displaying historical sale information
  * Sending you marketing, advertising, educational content and promotional messages and other information that may be of interest to you, including information about us, our Services, or general promotions for business partner campaigns and services. You can unsubscribe or opt-out from receiving these communications described below under “How You Can Protect Your Information”
  * To administer referral programs, rewards, surveys, sweepstakes, contests, or other promotional activities or events sponsored or managed by us or our business partners
  * In the case of retail stores, to share the name of the retail store with potential customers to encourage them to use our Services
  * Measuring, customising and improving the Services and developing new products
  * Sending to you service, support and administrative messages, reminders, technical notices, updates, security alerts and information requested by you
  * Investigating and preventing fraudulent transactions, unauthorised access to Services, and other illegal activities

Where we need your personal information for any other purposes, it will be obvious from the circumstances as to the purposes for which we require that personal information from you.

Sharing & disclosure of your information

When you use the Services, we may share your information only as described below:

Vend Blogs, Forums and Wikis

Our websites offer publicly accessible community services such as blogs, forums, and wikis. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. Your posts may remain even after you cancel your account. To request removal of your personal information from a Vend community service, please contact us using the information listed below. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to and why.

Service Providers, Business Partners and Others

We use and work with third party service providers and our trusted Business Partners to provide application development, hosting, website, infrastructure, maintenance, backup, payment processing, customer relationship management, marketing, accounting, human resources, business intelligence and analytics, data enrichment, customer support and other services for us. These service providers may have access to or process your information for the purpose of providing those services for us. Some of our pages use white-labelling techniques to serve content from our service providers while providing the look and feel of our site. Please note that you are providing your information to these third parties acting on behalf of Vend. These third parties are located in countries which may be outside of your location.

We also share your contact information with select trusted Business Partners, such as our partners who integrate with Vend services, to enable them to contact you about their services (as they relate to your Vend Services). We also obtain contact information from select Business Partners to better understand your preferences and to deliver you more personalised marketing.

Third Parties You Authorise

You can give third parties access to your and your end users’ information on the Services. For example, you may wish to integrate Vend with a third party appointment scheduling service that requires access to the email addresses you collect from your end users, in order for that appointment service to send reminder emails on your behalf and at your direction. Just be aware that such third party’s use of this information will be governed by the terms and privacy policies of the third party.

Links to Third Party Sites

Our Services may contain links to other sites. We have no control over, and take no responsibility for, the privacy practices or content on other sites. You are responsible for checking the privacy policy of any such sites so that you can be informed of how they handle personal information.

Social Media Widgets

Our Services may include social media features, such as the Facebook “Like” button and widgets, and the “Share” button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

Compliance with Laws and Protection of Rights

In certain situations, we may be required to use and disclose your information (including personal information) to a third party if we believe the disclosure is reasonably necessary:

  * To comply with any applicable law, legal process (for example, subpoenas and warrants) or governmental request
  * To enforce and administer our agreements, policies and terms of use
  * To protect the property, rights, and safety of Vend, our Subscribers or the public from harm or illegal activities
  * For fraud prevention, risk assessment, investigation, customer support, product development or debugging purposes
  * To protect the rights, property or personal safety of Vend, its users or members of the public
  * To establish or exercise our legal rights or defend ourselves against any third-party claims or allegations

Business Transfers

If Vend undertakes or is involved in any merger, acquisition, reorganization, sale of assets or bankruptcy or insolvency event, then we may transfer or share some or all of our assets, including your personal information. In this event, we will notify you before your personal information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy.

Non-identifying or Aggregated Data

We may share aggregated or other non-personal information that does not directly identify you with third parties in order to improve our Services.

Your Choices and Privacy Rights

**Updating your Personal Information via the Services:** You may access, change, or correct information about you by logging into your Vend account at any time or by making a request to us using the contact details below, in which case we may need to verify your identity before granting access or otherwise changing or correcting your information.

Account Information and Deactivating Your Account

If you wish to deactivate your Vend account, you may do so by logging into your Vend account and following these [instructions](https://support.vendhq.com/hc/en-us/signin?return_to=https%3A%2F%2Fsupport.vendhq.com%2Fhc%2Fen-us%2Farticles%2F201766580-Activating-Billing-and-Cancelling-Vend#cancel) or by emailing us using the contact details provided below.

Opting out of Promotional Communications

You may opt out of receiving promotional communications from Vend by using the unsubscribe link within each email or contacting us via our home page or sales team. Even after you opt out from receiving promotional messages from us, you will continue to receive transactional messages from us regarding Services (e.g., account verification, purchase and billing confirmations and reminders, technical and security notices).

Your California Privacy Rights

California law permits residents of California to request certain details about information we disclose to third parties for direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and would like to request this information, please contact us at the address listed below.

Your European Privacy Rights

In addition to the rights listed above, if you are in the EEA you also have rights to:

  * Know what personal information we hold about you, and to make sure it’s correct and up to date
  * Request a copy of your personal information or ask us to restrict processing of or delete it
  * Object to our continued processing of your personal information

If you’re not happy with how we are processing your personal information, you have the right to complain to your local information protection authority. Your local data protection authority will be able to give you more information on how to submit a complaint.

You can request to exercise these rights by emailing [privacy@vendhq.com](mailto:privacy@vendhq.com)

Cookies and Advertising

You may opt out of receiving cookies by instructing your browser to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from websites you visit, by changing your browser options.

You also can learn more about cookies by visiting [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/), which includes useful information on cookies and how to block cookies on different types of browsers and mobile devices.

Please note, however, that by blocking or deleting cookies used in Services, you may not be able to use all aspects of our Services.

Children’s use of the services

Services are not directed to individuals under 16. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 16. If we become aware that a child under 16 has provided us with personal information, we will take steps to delete such information. If you become aware that a child has provided us with personal information, please contact us at the address listed below.

Security

We have adopted technical, administrative and physical procedures to collect, manage, maintain and store information in a manner designed to help protect your information from loss, misuse, unauthorised access, and alteration. Unfortunately, no security system is impenetrable and due to the inherent nature of the Internet as an open global communications vehicle, we cannot guarantee that information, during transmission through the Internet or while stored on our systems or otherwise in our care, will be absolutely safe from intrusion by others, such as hackers.

Where data is transferred over the Internet as part of the Services, the data is encrypted using industry standard TLS (HTTPS).

For more information about our security practices, please visit www.vendhq.com/security.

Our global operations (including transfers of data from your home country to another)

To bring you Services, we operate globally. In order to do so, your personal information may be transferred to, and processed in countries other than the country you live in, outside of your home country, including to Australia, New Zealand, United Kingdom and the United States. These countries may have laws different to what you’re used to. Rest assured, where we disclose personal data to a third party in another country, we put safeguards in place to ensure your personal data remains protected.

Specifically, Vend hosts data with [Amazon Web Services](https://aws.amazon.com/) in the United States. If you are a non-US resident, this means that your personal information will be transferred to the US. The servers on which personal information is stored are kept in a controlled environment.

**European Economic Area (EEA) users:** This means that your information may be transferred outside of the EEA. Where your personal information is transferred outside the EEA, it will only be transferred to countries that have been deemed to provide adequate protection for EEA information (like New Zealand), or to a third party where we have approved transfer mechanisms in place to protect your personal information – i.e., by entering into the European Commission’s Standard Contractual Clauses, or by ensuring the entity is Privacy Shield certified (for transfers to US based third parties).

**Australian users:** The third parties we share data with do not control, and are not permitted to access or use your personal data, except for the limited purpose it was provided. This means that, for the purposes of Australian privacy legislation and Australian users, Vend does not disclose personal data to third parties located overseas

Information retention

Where we process your Subscriber Information, we retain personal information we collect from you where we have an ongoing legitimate business need to do so (in connection with the purposes set out above. For Information about how long any of our Subscribers retain your personal information, please contact that Subscriber.

When we have no ongoing legitimate business need to process your personal information, we will either delete or anonymise it or, if this is not possible (for example, because your personal information has been stored in backup archives), then we will securely store your personal information and isolate it from any further processing until deletion is possible.

Updates to our privacy policy

Vend reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy from time to time, and if we do we will post any changes on this page. Vend will make every effort to communicate any significant changes to you directly. Your continued use of the Services will be deemed acceptance of any updated policy.

Do You Have Questions?

Thanks for reading! If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or Vend’s privacy practices, please contact us at [privacy@vendhq.com](mailto:privacy@vendhq.com) or at our mailing address below:

Privacy Officer  
Vend Limited  
Level 1, 2 Nuffield Street  
Auckland, 1023  
New Zealand 

Note that the Vend companies operate as a group of individual data controllers. If you write to the address above, we will make sure that your request is dealt with by the appropriate part of Vend.

Copyright Ⓒ 2018 Vend
